Schenectady Labor Temple Association; Records apap035
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Schenectady Labor Temple Association Records
1912-1977
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Schenectady Labor Temple Association
apap035
8 cubic ft. processed to date
Founded in 1907, the Schenectady Labor Temple Association promotes labor relations and interests within Schenectady County, NY.
Access
Access to this record group is unrestricted.
Acquisition Information
All items in this manuscript group were lent to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, by the Schenectady Labor Temple Association for preservation photocopying as a part of the Harry Van Arsdale, Jr., Labor History Project. The originals have been returned to the Schenectady Labor Temple Association.
Organizational Sketch
The Schenectady Labor Temple Association was incorporated in 1907 and was primarily interested in the erection and then the management of the Schenectady Labor Temple. The Association has also been involved in promoting labor interests in Schenectady, New York, most obviously through the publication of an annual labor and business directory. The Schenectady Labor Temple was designed by Schenectady architect R. L. Bowen and completed in 1927 on the corner of Clinton and Liberty Streets. The Labor Temple provided office and meeting space for unions throughout eastern New York and extending as far north as the Canadian border.
Scope and Contents
The collection contains minutes of meetings, 1912–1958; yearbooks, 1931–1967; and by–laws, 1940s, 1960s.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is organized chronologically. There are no series.
Schenectady, New York; Labor; Labor unions -- Social aspects -- New York (State); Labor unions -- New York (State) -- Schenectady.; Minutes; Financial Records; Schenectady Labor Temple Association; Labor union locals
- Annual Report of the Utica Labor Temple, 1917 (Box 1 (Schenectady Labor Temple Association), Folder 1)
- Constitution and Bylaws, circa 1940s, 1960s (Box 1 (Schenectady Labor Temple Association), Folder 2)
- Correspondence with Department of Labor Concerning Labor Temple Construction, 1928 (Box 1 (Schenectady Labor Temple Association), Folder 3)
- Financial Reports, 1966, 1976-1977 (Box 1 (Schenectady Labor Temple Association), Folder 4)
- Labor and Business Directory, 1966, 1976-1977 (Box 1 (Schenectady Labor Temple Association), Folder 5)
- Minutes, 1912-1915 (Box 1 (Schenectady Labor Temple Association), Folder 6)
- Minutes, 1914-1915 (Box 1 (Schenectady Labor Temple Association), Folder 7)
- Minutes, 1915-1918 (Box 1 (Schenectady Labor Temple Association), Folder 8)
- Minutes, 1915-1918 (Box 1 (Schenectady Labor Temple Association), Folder 9)
- Minutes, 1918-1921 (Box 1 (Schenectady Labor Temple Association), Folder 10)
- Minutes, 1921-1925 (Box 1 (Schenectady Labor Temple Association), Folder 11)
- Minutes, 1926-1930 (Box 1 (Schenectady Labor Temple Association), Folder 12)
- Minutes, 1926-1930 (Box 1 (Schenectady Labor Temple Association), Folder 13)
- Minutes, 1930-1940 (Box 1 (Schenectady Labor Temple Association), Folder 14)
- Minutes, 1940-1945 (Box 2 (Schenectady Labor Temple Association), Folder 1)
- Minutes, 1946-1951 (Box 2 (Schenectady Labor Temple Association), Folder 2)
- Minutes, 1952-1958 (Box 2 (Schenectady Labor Temple Association), Folder 3)
- Newsclipping, 1956 (Box 2 (Schenectady Labor Temple Association), Folder 4)
- Minutes, 1921-1925 (Box 2 (Schenectady Labor Temple Association), Folder 5)
- Minutes, 1926-1930 (Box 2 (Schenectady Labor Temple Association), Folder 6)
- Minutes, 1926-1930 (Box 2 (Schenectady Labor Temple Association), Folder 7)
- Minutes, 1930-1940 (Box 2 (Schenectady Labor Temple Association), Folder 8)